Guide to the Daniel Rubin Papers TAM.657
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Youth Commission and Youth Organizations, 1924-1990; 12 Linear Feet in 18 manuscript boxes, 3 record cartons, and 1 cassette box; 2 audiocassettes
  - Labor Youth League: Documents, 1954-1955 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Labor Youth League: LYL Takes the Stand, 1954 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Labor Youth League: Marxism Classes, 1956-1959 (Box 226, Folder 29)
  - Labor Youth League: Public College, 1954-1955 (Box 227, Folder 1-2)
  - Labor Youth League: Publications, 1949-1957 (Box 76, Folder 7-8)
  - Labor Youth League: Publications, 1954 (Box 227, Folder 3)
  - Labor Youth League and Before, 1954-1958 (Box 227, Folder 4-5)
  - League Life: A Handbook, 1978 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - League Type Groups, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 6)
  - Military Spending and Economy, 1977-1978 (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Youth Publications (YWLL, YCL, LYL), 1954 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - National Coalition for Economic Justice: Youth March for Jobs, 1980 (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - National Inner Party Youth, circa 1960 (Box 77, Folder 5-6)
  - National Student Conference: Wisconsin, 1952 (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - National Youth Secretary: Strategy and Correspondence, 1964 (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - New Challenge and Other LYL Publications, 1953 (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - New Challenge, 1954-1956 (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - New Horizons for Youth, 1960-1964 (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - New Horizons for Youth: Distribution, 1960-1961 (Box 227, Folder 7)
  - New Horizons for Youth: Endorsements, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 8)
  - National Youth Organization: Organizing Committee: National Convention, 1970 (Box 78, Folder 1-3)
  - Paid Bills, 1963, 1977 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Park Slope: Youth March, 1978 (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Party Youth Program and National Youth Act, 1959-1960 (Box 78, Folder 6-8)
  - Philadelphia, PA: Youth Education, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 9)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee (PYOC): Collaboration with Youth Organizations, 1961-1963 (Box 227, Folder 10-12)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee (PYOC): Conference Materials, 1960-1961 (Box 227, Folder 13-15)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee (PYOC): Education, 1964 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee (PYOC): New Horizons for Youth, 1960 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee (PYOC): Pamphlets and Flyers, 1961-1964 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee (PYOC): Programs and Statements, 1961-1963 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - Progressive Youth Organizing Committee and Du Bois Clubs, 1964 (Box 227, Folder 16)
  - Puerto Rican Work, 1954-1985 (Box 79, Folder 5-6)
  - Queen, Da, 1983 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - Socialist Youth Founding Convention, 1964 (Box 227, Folder 18)
  - Student Civil Rights, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 19)
  - Students for Democratic Action: NAACP and Other Groups, 1955-1956 (Box 227, Folder 20)
  - Student Public Activity: Labor Youth League and SSSP, 1955-1966 (Box 227, Folder 21)
  - Swarthmore: Intercollegiate Conference: "By What Means Peace?", 1951 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - Swarthmore: Youth Progressives of America (YPA), 1950-1951 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Swarthmore: Young Progressives of America (YPA), East-West Club, 1951-1953 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - Young Progressives of America (YPA), 1948-1953 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - White House Conference, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 22)
  - World Festival of Youth and Students, 1978 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - World Youth Festival, 8th, 1961 (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - World Youth Festival, 8th, 1962 (Box 227, Folder 23)
  - Writings on Youth, 1960 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Writings on Youth, 1960 (Box 80, Folder 1-4)
  - Young Communist League, 1924-1943, undated (Box 80, Folder 5-6)
  - Young Communist League: Campaign, 1985-1987 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Young Communist League: Conventions, 1990 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Young Communist League: Documents, 1984 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Young Communist League: "Dynamic" Fund Drive, 1983 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Young Communist League: Education, 1978 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Young Communist League: Festival History, 1985 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Young Communist League: General, 1982-1983 (Box 80, Folder 13-14)
  - Young Communist League: History of Building the League, 1983 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Young Communist League: Minutes and Policy Statements, 1960-1961 (Box 228, Folder 1)
  - Young Communist League and American Youth for Democracy, 1960-1962 (Box 227, Folder 24-25)
  - Young Communist League/Labor Youth League, 1954, 1980-1990 (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Young (Communist) Workers Liberation League: Founding, 1968-1969 (Box 81, Folder 3-8)
  - Young (Communist) Workers Liberation League: Founding, 1969 (Box 82, Folder 1-2)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: Convention, 2nd, 1971-1972 (Box 82, Folder 3-5)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: Convention, 4th, 1977-1978 (Box 82, Folder 6-8)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: Convention, 4th, 1977-1978 (Box 83, Folder 1-2)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: Convention, 5th, 1981 (Box 83, Folder 3-5)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: General, 1970-1973 (Box 83, Folder 6-8)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: General, 1970-1983 (Box 84, Folder 1-10)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: General, 1977-1983 (Box 85, Folder 1-10)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: General, 1980-1983 (Box 86, Folder 1-6)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: Publications, 1969-1985 (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: Publications, 1974-1977 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Young Workers Liberation League: Seminar, 1978 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Young Workers Liberation League and Young Communist League, 1980s, 1981-1984 (Box 87, Folder 3-5)
  - Youth, undated (Box 234, Cassette 65-66)
  - Youth: Basics, 1960-1964 (Box 87, Folder 7-8)
  - Youth: Documents, 1960s (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Youth: Economy, 1980 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Youth: Economy, 1979-1980 (Box 88, Folder 1-2)
  - Youth: Finance Book, 1963 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - Youth: Finances, 1982-1983 (Box 88, Folder 4-6)
  - Youth: Jobs, 1977-1978 (Box 88, Folder 7-9)
  - Youth: Jobs, 1970s-1980s, 1981 (Box 89, Folder 1-2)
  - Youth: Jobs Action, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Youth: Jobs Bill, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Youth Act, 1979 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Youth Commission, 1959-1963 (Box 227, Folder 2-4)
  - Youth Department: Extra, 1971-1973 (Box 227, Folder 5-6)
  - Youth Education, circa 1960s (Box 227, Folder 7)
  - Youth Encampment, 1964 (Box 227, Folder 8-9)
  - Youth History: Communist Party Education, 1983 (Box 227, Folder 10)
  - Youth and Labor: Reports, 1950-1979 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Youth March for Jobs, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 6-8)
  - Youth March for Jobs, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 1-4)
  - Youth March for Jobs: Materials to be Turned In, circa 1979 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Youth March for Jobs: Media, 1978 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Youth Miscellaneous, 1983 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Youth Publications, 1962-1963 (Box 227, Folder 11)
  - Youth Publications: Oregon and Washington, 1960-1961 (Box 227, Folder 12)
  - Youth Publications: Pennsylvania, Eastern, 1960 (Box 227, Folder 13)
  - Youth Question, 1962-1987 (Box 90, Folder 8-9)
  - Youth Question: Theory and Strategy, 1960-1964 (Box 91, Folder 1-7)
  - Youth Readings, 1954-1964 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Youth Report: Convention, 18th, 1963 (Box 227, Folder 14)
  - Youth Work: Communist Viewpoint, 1960-1964 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Youth Work: Philadelphia, 1958 (Box 227, Folder 15)
  - Youth Work: Philadelphia: Education, circa 1958 (Box 227, Folder 16)
- Series III: Economic and Social Rights Commission, 1979-1990; 10.5 Linear Feet in 19 manuscript boxes and 2 record cartons
  This series contains memos, notes, bulletins, correspondence and resolutions related to Rubin's work as the director of the Economic and Social Rights Commission from 1974-1980. The series largely relates to two major campaigns that the Party supported, the National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment and the National Coalition for Economic Justice. The series also includes articles, outlines, and research materials on a variety of social issues that were prevalent in the late 1970s.
  Files in this series are arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Affirmative Action, 1977-1978 (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - AFL-CIO Solidarity Day, 1981 (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - Africa: New York Times, 1979 (Box 228, Folder 17)
  - Afro-American Equality, 1967, 1970s, 1983 (Box 92, Folder 1-4)
  - Afro-American Equality Basics, 1989 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Afro-American Equality and Economy, 1979-1980 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Children, circa 1970s (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Coalition for Economic Survival (Southern California), 1974-1976 (Box 247, Folder 3-4)
  - Committee for Alternative Action, circa 1970s (Box 247, Folder 5)
  - Committee for Full Employment -- Philadelphia, 1975 (Box 247, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Inflation: Washington, D.C., 1974 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Inflation: Washington, D.C., 1974 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Conference on Independent Positions, 1976-1977 (Box 93, Folder 2-3)
  - Countries: Various, India, 1989 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Countries: Various, World, 1988 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Crossroads, 1990 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Cunningham, Frank, 1976 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Daily World, 1977-1980 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Department Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 93, Folder 9-10)
  - Department Notes, 1977-1978 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - Department Notes, 1978-1979 (Box 94, Folder 1-2)
  - Department Notes: Districts, 1977-1980 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Department Notes: Young Workers Communist League, 1979-1980 (Box 94, Folder 4-5)
  - Economic Commission: Minutes and Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 228, Folder 19)
  - Economic Coalition, 1974-1978 (Box 228, Folder 20)
  - Economic Department: General, 1975-1979 (Box 94, Folder 6-8)
  - Economic Names and Numbers: Contact Information, 1974-1976 (Box 95, Folder 1-2)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: African Solidarity, 1973-1980 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: Anti-Nuclear and Peace, 1975-1980 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: Criminal Justice, 1959, 1976 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: Elections, 1980 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: International Issues, 1973-1980 (Box 95, Folder 7-8)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: Israel and Jews, 1980 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: Labor, 1971-1980 (Box 96, Folder 2-3)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: New York, 1975-1987 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: Race and Civil Rights, 1973-1979 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Economic and Social Rights: Collected Ephemera: Women, 1979 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Economic and Social Rights Seminar, 1978 (Box 229, Folder 1)
  - Economic Ultra Left and Social Democrats, 1977 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Economics, circa 1978 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Economy, 1980 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Economy -- General, 1975-1976 (Box 247, Folder 7-10)
  - Economy Statement, 1980 (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Education and Psychology, 1980 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Employment, 1977 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Eurocommunism, 1978 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Farm and Rural Commission, 1976 (Box 228, Folder 18)
  - Health, 1978-1979 (Box 97, Folder 1-6)
  - Health, 1978-1988 (Box 98, Folder 1-2, Box 247, Folder 11)
  - Health: Chicago Coalition for a National Health Service, 1978 (Box 228, Folder 21)
  - Health Bills, 1979-1981 (Box 98, Folder 3-5)
  - Health Bills, 1979-1981 (Box 99, Folder 1-4)
  - Health Commission, 1973-1978 (Box 228, Folder 22)
  - Health Commission: Reports and Articles, 1977 (Box 228, Folder 23-25)
  - Health Reports, 1979 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Health Section: Meeting Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 228, Folder 26)
  - Health Section: Meeting and Reports, 1977 (Box 228, Folder 27)
  - Homosexuality, 1977-1979 (Box 99, Folder 7-9)
  - Housing, 1976 (Box 100, Folder 1, Box 247, Folder 12)
  - Human Rights Committee: Health, 1979 (Box 100, Folder 2-4)
  - Indian Liberation, 1971-1973 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Inflation, 1978 (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - International Economics and Liberation, 1973-1976 (Box 248, Folder 1)
  - Mass Party Organizing Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 248, Folder 2)
  - Military Spending, 1974-1975 (Box 248, Folder 3)
  - Money from Pamphlets, 1976 (Box 100, Folder 7)
  - National Action Mass, Economic, 1977 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - National Action Mass, Economic, 1977 (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - National Coalition for Economic Justice, 1977-1981 (Box 101, Folder 2-6)
  - National Coalition for Economic Justice, 1977-1980 (Box 102, Folder 1-7)
  - National Coalition for Economic Justice, 1976-1983 (Box 103, Folder 1-3)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment/National Coalition for Economic Justice, 1974-1981 (Box 103, Folder 4)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Adults, 1972-1977 (Box 103, Folder 5-7)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Congressman John Conyers Dinner, 1977 (Box 103, Folder 8)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Conference, 1975 (Box 103, Folder 9)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Finances, 1971-1975 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Founding, 1974 (Box 104, Folder 2)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: General, 1974-1976 (Box 248, Folder 4-10, Box 249, Folder 1)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Legislative Conference, 1975 (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Legislation Materials, 1976 (Box 104, Folder 4-5)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Local Coalitions, 1974-1975 (Box 249, Folder 2-3)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: March for Jobs (Washington, D.C.), 1975 (Box 104, Folder 6-8)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: March for Jobs (Washington, D.C.), 1975-1976 (Box 105, Folder 1-3, Box 249, Folder 4)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: November 16th Protest, 1974 (Box 105, Folder 4-6)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Speak Out to President Carter, 1977 (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Washington, D.C. Action, 1976 (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - National Coalition to Fight Inflation and Unemployment: Youth, 1976 (Box 106, Folder 1, Box 249, Folder 5)
  - National Coalition Minutes, 1975-1978 (Box 106, Folder 2-3)
  - National Committee to Re-Open the Rosenberg's Case, 1976 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - National Economic Indicators, 1974-1976 (Box 249, Folder 6-7)
  - National Laws, 1975 (Box 106, Folder 5-6)
  - National Legislation, 1975-1976 (Box 229, Folder 2-4)
  - National Legislation: Employment, 1973-1979 (Box 229, Folder 5-7)
  - National Legislation: Youth Employment, 1971-1981 (Box 229, Folder 8)
  - New American Movement, 1978-1980 (Box 106, Folder 7-10)
  - Nixon Economic Policy, 1971 (Box 229, Folder 9)
  - November 16th Actions Against Inflation, 1972-1976 (Box 107, Folder 1-3)
  - November 16th: Endorsers, 1974 (Box 107, Folder 4)
  - November 16th: Entertainment, 1974 (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Puerto Rico, 1983-1987 (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Roberson Documents, 1978 (Box 107, Folder 7-8)
  - Seniors, 1973-1980 (Box 107, Folder 9-10)
  - Shorter Workday, early 1970s (Box 249, Folder 8)
  - South America: Resolutions, 1977 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Southern Africa: Collected Publications, 1974-1978 (Box 229, Folder 10)
  - Southern Africa: Notes and Research, 1980 (Box 229, Folder 11)
  - Trade Unions, Working Class and Labor, 1984-1987 (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Unemployment, circa 1981, 1983 (Box 108, Folder 3-4)
  - Utilities, 1977 (Box 249, Folder 9)
  - Voz del Pueblo, 1984-1985 (Box 108, Folder 5-6)
  - Women, 1973-1979 (Box 108, Folder 7-11)
  - Women, 1977 (Box 109, Folder 1)
  - Women's Commission, 1967-1981 (Box 109, Folder 2-4)
  - Youth Rights, 1979 (Box 109, Folder 5)
- Series IV: Education Department, 1930s-1997; 19.5 Linear Feet in 34 manuscript boxes, 2 record cartons, and 3 cassette boxes; 6 audiocassettes
  This series includes course outlines, research, recruiting material, and coordinating materials for the Communist Party's National Education Department, dated largely during the 1980s. The series includes National Education Department correspondence and administrative files as well as study guides, notes on curriculum, registration files, and lecture notes for National Party Schools and Regional Schools. The series also includes discussion guides, outlines, and lecture notes on topical courses and seminar series, which cover themes like the working class, Marxism, leadership, and the economy.
  - Action Committee for Education, undated (Box 109, Folder 6)
  - Afro-American Question, 1969-1985 (Box 109, Folder 7)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies (AIMS), 1985 (Box 109, Folder 8-9)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies (AIMS), 1985 (Box 110, Folder 1)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: Aptheker Dinner, 1984 (Box 110, Folder 2)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: Aptheker Dinner, Ledger, 1984 (Box 110, Folder 3)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: Aptheker Letters, 1983-1986 (Box 110, Folder 4)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: Harlem Mailing List, 1984 (Box 110, Folder 5)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: Money Receipts, Pledges, Aptheker Dinner, 1984 (Box 110, Folder 6-7)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: Newsletters, 1982-1987 (Box 110, Folder 8-9)
  - American Institute for Marxist Studies: Newsletters, 1982-1987 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Asian-Pacific Material, 1988-1989 (Box 111, Folder 2)
  - Academic Work 1-2, 1984-1987 (Box 111, Folder 3-7)
  - Academic Work 3-7, 1980-1989 (Box 112, Folder 1-10)
  - Chicago Worker's School, 1982 (Box 229, Folder 12)
  - Classes: Notes and Outlines, circa 1960s (Box 229, Folder 13)
  - Classes: Notes and Schedules, 1961 (Box 229, Folder 14)
  - Classes for Schools, 1986 (Box 113, Folder 1)
  - Club Educational Unemployed Struggles, 1982 June (Box 237, Cassette 178)
  - Communist Party: Theory of, 1971 (Box 113, Folder 2)
  - Daily Leadership Seminar, 1988 (Box 113, Folder 3)
  - Daily National School, 1987 (Box 113, Folder 4)
  - Danny School: Mon #1, undated (Box 238, Cassette 193)
  - Danny School: Mon #3, 1980s (Box 238, Cassette 194)
  - Department Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 113, Folder 5-6)
  - Department Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 229, Folder 15)
  - Dialectical Materialism, 1960-1971 (Box 113, Folder 8-11)
  - Dialectical Materialism: Philosophy, 1981-1985 (Box 113, Folder 12-13)
  - Discussion Outlines, circa 1950s (Box 229, Folder 16)
  - Discussion Outlines, 1980s (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Discussion Outlines: Youth Commission, 1960-1965 (Box 229, Folder 17)
  - Dimitrov, G. 100th Birthday, 1982 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Diskin, Lou: Course Outlines and Notes, 1985-1991 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Diskin, Lou: From Danny Rubin, undated (Box 114, Folder 3-8)
  - Discussion on Classes: Youth Commission, 1965 (Box 229, Folder 18)
  - Discussion Materials: Marxism Readings, 1960s-1970s, 1983-1997, 1988-1996 (Box 115, Folder 1-6)
  - Discussion Materials: On International Fascism and World War II, 1930s-1940s (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Discussion Outlines and Study Guides, 1930s-1940s (Box 115, Folder 8-10)
  - Discussion Outlines and Study Guides, 1940s-1950s, 1952-1960, 1965-1991 (Box 116, Folder 1-6)
  - Discussion Outlines and Study Guides: African American Question, 1939-1952 (Box 116, Folder 7)
  - Discussion Outlines and Study Guides: African Americans and Racism, 1950s (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Discussion Outlines and Study Guides: Communism in Asia, 1952-1959 (Box 117, Folder 2)
  - District Leadership Classes: Ohio, Michigan, Wisconsin, Missouri, 1982 (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - District Papers, 1983-1987 (Box 117, Folder 4)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B: Articles, 1952-1958 (Box 117, Folder 5)
  - Du Bois-Foster School of Marxism Leninism, 1978 (Box 117, Folder 6)
  - Du Bois-Foster School for Marxist Studies: Booking Change Schedule, 1977 (Box 229, Folder 19)
  - Ecology, 1983 (Box 117, Folder 7)
  - Ecology: Environment, 1986 (Box 117, Folder 8)
  - Economic Bill of Rights, 1982 (Box 117, Folder 9)
  - Economics: Basic Political Economy, 1986 (Box 117, Folder 10)
  - Economics: Exploitation, undated (Box 117, Folder 11)
  - Economy, 1986 (Box 117, Folder 12)
  - Economy: Basics, 1985, 1991 (Box 117, Folder 13-14)
  - Economy: Basics and WMR Article, 1986-1987 (Box 118, Folder 1)
  - Education: Central Committee Meeting, 1981 December (Box 237, Cassette 177)
  - Education: Lecture Notes and Discussion Questions, 1966-1969 (Box 229, Folder 20)
  - Education: Legislation, 1968-1969 (Box 229, Folder 21)
  - Education: Miscellaneous, 1972-1979, 1983-1986 (Box 118, Folder 2-3)
  - Education Commission, 1988-1991 (Box 118, Folder 4-7)
  - Education Commission: Club Outline, 1990 (Box 118, Folder 8)
  - Education Commission: Questionnaire and Responses, undated (Box 119, Folder 1)
  - Education Department, 1981-1983 (Box 119, Folder 2-10)
  - Education Department, 1983 (Box 120, Folder 1-7)
  - Education Department, 1984-1988 (Box 121, Folder 1-10)
  - Education on Party Organization, circa 1947 (Box 229, Folder 22)
  - Education and Racism, 1991 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Education Work on Afro-Equality and Racism, 1988 (Box 122, Folder 2-4)
  - Education Video, 1989 (Box 122, Folder 5)
  - Exposure Materials for Education, 1960s-1970s (Box 229, Folder 23)
  - Films, 1983-1984 (Box 122, Folder 6)
  - Fischer Intelligence and Russia, 1986 (Box 122, Folder 7)
  - Fundamentals of Marxism-Leninism, 1960 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Gil Green on Social History, 1988 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - Historical Materialism, 1960s-1970s, 1985 (Box 123, Folder 1-2)
  - History Commission, 1987 (Box 123, Folder 3)
  - History of CPUSA, 1969 (Box 123, Folder 4)
  - Labor, 1988 (Box 123, Folder 5-6)
  - Labor Education, 1983 (Box 123, Folder 7)
  - Leadership Seminar, 1971 (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Leadership Seminar: Food, Housing, Finances, 1988 (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - Leadership Seminar: Registrations, Outlines, etc., 1988 (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Leadership Seminar Materials, 1988 (Box 124, Folder 2-5)
  - Leadership Seminar - Daniel Rubin Teaching, 1988 (Box 124, Folder 6)
  - Lenin: Self-Study, undated (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Leninism Class, 1983 (Box 124, Folder 8)
  - Library Materials: Reference Center for Marxist Studies, 1983-1990 (Box 124, Folder 9)
  - Literature: Conference, 1988 (Box 125, Folder 1)
  - Literature: Pamphlets, 1983 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Literature: Posters, 1983 (Box 125, Folder 3-4)
  - A Manual for Educational Directors (Photocopy), 1937 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Marx Centennial Anniversary, 1983 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Marx-Lenin Quotes, 1890-1920, 1983 (Box 125, Folder 7-9)
  - Marxism and Natural Science, 1967 (Box 125, Folder 10)
  - Marxist Education, 1977-1979 (Box 125, Folder 11)
  - Marxist Schools, 1988 December 11 (Box 236, Cassette 120)
  - Marxist Theory: Aesthetics and Literature, 1968 (Box 125, Folder 12)
  - Mass Media, 1982-1983 (Box 126, Folder 1-2)
  - "Materialist Approach to History" by David Montgomery, undated (Box 229, Folder 24-25)
  - "Materialist Approach to History" by David Montgomery, undated (Box 230, Folder 1)
  - Mixed District and Club Classes, 1982 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - National Board Educational: Updating Indictment of Capitalism, 1989 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - National Board and Secretariat: Education, 1986-1987 (Box 126, Folder 5)